better time to do five minute video and
five minutes for my kid gets dropped off
from the bus one take and that's it it's
all we got time for camera don't talk
about today I'm gonna do a hundred
videos sit down figure out what I'm
trying to do with them and beginning and
I was trying to explain the global
cooperative which i think is better done
in book format although I might continue
to do that because best case worst case
scenario I horribly messed that up for
70 odd days and gets me closer to the
language I'm trying to use to better
explain it so yeah today is day 29 and I
spent my hour of writing coffee shop
ready on this sleeve didn't like I was
in high school again and went to hang
out with my friend and her baby for
today don't feel like I accomplished
much as far as explaining the global
poverty I don't know anything more the
more I learned the less I know my child
seems to think she knows everything
try to explain to her that that means
you don't that with age comes the
understanding that the more you know the
less time the more learn you learn how
little you know even in my areas of
expertise I'm gonna have a degree in
science I only I know like a drop in the
bucket of science even with PhD and
study your whole life you know what drop
in the bucket of science
just why we need to come together and
figure out the big picture together why
I'm trying to explain this little
operative and he's being so frustrated I
just like literally bang myself on laid
my head on the table and scream like
every time anything happens to do with I
mean the natural disaster is related to
climate change and Wars and quality and
just I get why the world is depressed
and dysfunctional and I have a solution
it's not perfect doesn't mean it's not
going to take work won't be imposed
overnight but as we're able to build the
solutions together and create the
systems to cooperate and make it a lot
easier for people to give the gifts that
they were put on earth to give instead
of us all struggling to figure it out
all struggling it to find out why we're
here and having to go through this
process that I'm going through if like
when you have the solution how do you
get it out there how do you get it in
the hands of the right people when you
don't have necessarily the money or
you're not the best speaker to explain
it to people how do you get the interior
in your brain out to the exterior how do
you when you're a piece of the puzzle
when you you know have this great idea
for a novel but you only know the
characters and you're not a good writer
but someone else is a good writer or
vice versa maybe you're good at writing
but you don't know you're not gonna
character or whatever but there are
pieces of the puzzle to come together
instead of being all things for a
project to be able to allow ourselves to
be a piece of it and to do what we're
here to do in the systems and because
for all of that explaining it in a way
that is articulate and makes sense and
people don't have I mean of course we're
going to questions and statements and
find fault with it I'm more than happy
with that but if I don't it's a one-way
conversation like a video or a book that
needs to I need to explain the most
commonly brought up problems because
they're gonna stop people like oh yeah
but what about this it's like yes and
the 20 other people pointed that out and
here's my solution to that and you can't
do that in a five-minute talk and coming
to grips with that this isn't a
five-minute presentation it is a novel
and maybe it's a 10 page novel maybe
it's 100 page or a thousand page novel
but I need to be able to write that
novel I need to be able to write all of
the different pieces and the more I have
that conversation with different people
and they point out potential issues and
I'm able to come up with potential
solutions to those issues that makes it
stronger it doesn't make it weaker so I
can point out all the problems even the
few that I have that I don't have
solutions to first of all the collective
brain is gonna have better solutions
than I could ever come up with for any
of the issues so the issues that I can't
solve then we can we can handle and even
with those issues even in those areas
one of them being racism and diversity
and how you like allow everyone to be a
part of it but not have hate talk right
like how do you find that balance and I
mean the balance of zero hate talk and I
miss balance but like where people can
be racist they can be a racist
homophobic human being and still be
invited to be part of the conversation
but not invited to be racist homophobic
I mean I don't know what the solution
chat is but a system that allows you to
have those conversations is infinitely
better than what we have going on now or
we're just denying it we don't have the
truth and we don't know it's you know
you can spin it either way because there
is no one place to go for four answers
that's trustworthy that we can point to
so ya know somebody talking for five
minutes the bus should be here soon and
this is day 29